# Eliza Starr

## Data Scientist

Ocharleston, South Carolina, USA

eliza.r.starr@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/elizastarr1

www.elizastarr.com

## Summary

**Data Scientist** with a solid foundation in computer science, mathematics, and statistics. Industry and Research experience in Residential Real Estate, Corporate Real Estate, and Hospitality and Tourism Management. Knowledgable about data cleaning and exploration processes, natural language processing, time series forecasting, supervised and unsupervised learning algorithms, and data visualization and storytelling.

## **Education**

#### **Bachelor of Science, Data Science**

Aug 2015 - May 2019

College of Charleston

GPA 4.0 / 4.0

President's List of Highly Distinguished Honors

## **Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science**

Aug 2015 - May 2019

College of Charleston

GPA 3.9 / 4.0

President's List of Highly Distinguished Honors

# Work experience

#### **Data Science Intern**

May 2018 - Aug 2018

#### BoomTown

Utilized python and techniques such as classification, natural language processing, time series forecasting, and cluster analysis to extract information and predictions from sales, customer churn, and user data

#### **Project Manager and Internal Marketing Intern**

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016

#### Boeing

Reengineered a web-based Kanban board, contributing through front end, project manager, and UX roles Created a repeatable process to visually market the business value of every IT function

#### Web Development Intern

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

Yawper Ventures LLC

Developed the single-page website for the start-up company Yawper, now dissolved

#### Research

#### **Text Analysis of Airbnb Reviews**

Jul 2018 - present

Data Science Research, College of Charleston Hospitality and Tourism

#### Management

Investigates if Airbnb reviews reflect that guests' lodging experiences differ in meaningful ways as a function of the type of Airbnb accommodation used. This research paper is in the data analysis stage.

### Visual and Text Analysis of Software Companies

Jan 2018 - present

Data Analytics Research, College of Charleston Real Estate

Analyzes the relationship of software company culture, core values, and project management methodologies on the demand for corporate real estate, impacting decisions regarding location, square footage, office design and amenities. This research paper is in review for publication.

## **Core Competencies**

- Supervised Learning
- Unsupervised Learning
- Data Mining
- Artificial Intelligence
- Time Series Forecasting
- Visualization
- Business Analytics

- Parametric Statistics
- Statistical Inference
- Statistical Learning
- Linear Algebra
- Calculus
- Discrete Mathematics
- Algorithms
- Data Structures
- Databases
- Operating Systems
- Software Architecture
- Software Design

#### **Skills**

Languages	Python, SQL, Java, R, C, PHP
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Neo4j
Visualization	Plotly, Tableau
Collaboration	Git, GitHub, Agile methodologies, Kanban, Slack